Joey Chau

FRONT END DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a web developer with project management experience, and a background in technical engineering design. My passion for building things, puzzle-solving, and all things aesthetic has fueled me in developing responsive and accessible web apps with dry, reusable code.

EDUCATION

Juno College — Web Development Immersive AUG 2020 - OCT 2020

University of Toronto — BASc in Mechanical Engineering SEP 2009 - JUN 2015

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- React
- JavaScript & jQuery
- Git & GitHub
- REST APIs / Firebase
- HTML5, CSS3, SCSS
- WCAG Accessibility
- Responsive Design
- Analytical Thinking
- Time Management

CONTACT INFORMATION

(416) 417-3109 joeymchau@gmail.com

Portfolio: www.chaujoey.con GitHub

RECENT PROJECTS

fresh vibes — React / Firebase

A music-blogging platform for users to share tracks and albums from bandcamp. Users can like their favourite posts, and create their own posts with banner images provided by the Unpslash API.

view live here

Komami Code — jQuery / SCSS

A fully responsive memory game influenced by the Konami Code. Keyboard users can use the WASD keys to mimic directions, and touch screen users can tap the d-pad on the controller on the screen.

view live here

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

APR 2020 - Present

- Designed and built a responsive multi-page
 eCommerce website with jQuery and Bootstrap
- Instructed client on using Contentful API GUI to dynamically add and remove products from the website

view live here

Quality and Project Engineer — ACS Corp.

APR 2018 - APR 2020

- Implemented strict form control on data logs using VBA for better search capabilities, and discourage non-descriptive records
- Established timelines for new product launches, minimizing gap in product supply for contract customers
- Created project proposals for automotive OEM clients in accordance to IATF Standards
- Promoted within 1 year for establishing document standards for product life cycles, increasing rate of project approvals by 40%